MARK VITAL

Victoria, BC ○ linktr.ee/markvital
□ markvital.eth
□ +1(347)8555133

markvital.x@gmail.com

Full Stack Web Developer

PROFILE

I'm a full stack developer leaning towards front-end with an eye for user interfaces and a sense of usability and hands-on experience building products from scratch.

I have worked in large corporations for half of my career and in a startups later on. I feel like I have now combined both the professionalism of working on advanced products with the hacker mindset of a startup. I lean towards using open-sources frameworks, tools to achieve fast results balancing with software best practices.

SKILLS

- Front end: React.js, ES6 Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS (modules, styled c.), SVG, MUI
- Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Jest, Laravel (I've come to appreciate the MERN stack more lately), Jekyll, Java, PHP, static state generators (Gatsby.js, Next.js), AWS, Docker, Nginx, GraphQL, REST, TypeORM, Type-DI, Postgres
- Web3: solid understanding of core Web3 concepts like cryptocurrency, tokens, smart contracts, NFT, DAO, wallets, IPFS, ethers.js
- Design: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, Figma, UI sketching and prototyping, infographics
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Webpack, ESLint, Chrome DevTools, GitHub, Docker, npm, Cypress, Postman, LLMs, Tableau, SpreadSheets
- Best Practices: CI/CD, version control (git), TDD, DRY, KISS, Agile, Kanban
- Leadership: comfortable leading small teams, mentorship, compassionate coding

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER, UNSTOPPABLE DOMAINS, - MAY - NOV 2022

Worked on user profiles pages that link to their NFT domain names and user-uploaded NFTs. Improved domain search features. Worked on domain management that interacted with smart contracts and NFT cache.

Tech: React.js, Node.js, TypeScript, Next.js, Material UI, Google Cloud, Moralis Web3 API, OpenSea API, ethers.js

LEAD DEVELOPER / CTO, ADIOMA PTE.LTD. - 2016-2022

Building from scratch a web-based graphics editor for generating information graphics. Launched as a SAAS, got to 100,000 users /3,000 paying customers.

I was leading a team of developers, also doing product design and testing.

Tech: React.js, PHT, Laravel, REST, MySQL, FastSpring, Elastic Search, NGinx, OVH Cloud

DEVELOPER / DATA VISUALIZATION, FNF LABS - 2012-2016

Created data visualizations and infographics using D3.js, Javascript, SVG, Python for companies such as Google, Cisco, Thermofisher Scientific, World Bank, and many others.

Tech: D3.js, React.js, SVG, CSS animation, Tableu, Open Refine, FreeBase, AWS, Wordpress

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GOOGLE - 2010-2011

Contributed to a web-based tool that tests HTML features across different browsers. I maintained the test runner written in Java and wrote new tests in Javascript.

Tech: Java, Python, JavaScript, HTML, various internal Google framework and tools

SENIOR JAVA DEVELOPER, WEBMD - 2009-2010

Integrated a drug interaction API with the existing application that catalogs drugs. Using Java and Javascript, I built a tool that allowed our users (doctors) to look up multiple drugs and explore the results of their interaction.

Tech: Java, Spring Framework, Hibernate ORM, MySQL, Nginx, Linux

EDUCATION

KYIV POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY - B.S. AND M.S. IN APPLIED MATH (2008)

HOBBIES

SWIMMING, HIKING, PLAYING GO, SCI-FI MOVIES, INFOGRAPHICS

PORTFOLIO

HTTPS://MARKVITAL.GITHUB.IO